Guide to the Rutherfurd Collection 1642-1845 MS 531
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Correspondence and Documents, 1642-1845 (bulk 1734-1796)
  - Subseries I.C: Volume II, 1734-1742
    - [3] Deposition of Alexander Campbell, 1734 June 17
    - [3] Letter from Captain Hugh Munro to his Excellency the Governor, 1734 June 18
    - [3] On Sunday last I received..., Undated
    - [5] Draft of letter for Captain Hugh Munro to Governor William Cosby, 1734 June 15
    - [5] Letter from Rev. Alexander Campbell to James Alexander, 1734 November 20
    - [7] Letter from James Alexander to Thomas Hunter, 1734 July 12
    - [8] Notice of the silencing of James Alexander and William Smith, 1734 April 16
    - [9] Copy of Bill filed against John Peter Zenger, 1735 January
    - [9] Subpoena from Justice of Supreme Court for John Peter Zenger, 1735 July 11
    - [9] Power of Attorney to Messrs. Alexander and Smith from John Peter Zenger, 1734 November 18
    - [9] New York Supreme Court - John Peter Zenger [Copy of Bill?], 1735
    - [11] Argument by Zenger's Counsel upon his right of admission to bail, 1734 March 20
    - [13] John Peter Zenger: Exception filed, p. 1-2; trial material, 1734 November 23
    - [15] John Peter Zenger: Exception filed, p. 3-4; trial material, 1734 November 23
    - [17] John Peter Zenger: Exception filed, p. 5-6; trial material, 1734 November 23
    - [19] John Peter Zenger: Exception filed, p. 7-8; trial material, 1734 November 23
    - [21] John Peter Zenger: Objection, 1734 November 23
    - [22] John Peter Zenger: Jury List, Undated
    - [23] Trial of John Peter Zenger, Mr. Hamilton as his Counsel, 1735 August 4
    - [23] The list of Zenger's jury as struck, 1735 August 4
    - [24] Memorandum of Exceptions as to jurisdiction of court as taken by Messrs. Alexander and Smith, in the legality of the Judges' Commissions, 1735 April 15
    - [25] Dangerous..., 1735 August 4
    - [25] Upon this Mr. Alexander, 1735 April
    - [27] Tryals..., Undated
    - [29] Whether imprisoned for..., Undated
    - [31] Stake tryas Vol 3 to 854..., Undated
    - [32] 459..., Undated
    - [33] Skiner 574..., 1735
    - [33] Doctrine of Lybel, Undated
    - [35] John Peter Zenger: information for Lybelling, Undated
    - [37] Reigns & the manifest p. 2-3, Undated
    - [39] Stake tryals Vol 5... p. 4-5, Undated
    - [41] As to that part of No. 13... p.6-7, Undated
    - [43] As to erecting... p. 8-9, Undated
    - [45] it will be... p. 10-11, Undated
    - [47] terms as any other p. 12-13, Undated
    - [49] Influence over p. 14-15, Undated
    - [51] Would be to have... p. 16-17, Undated
    - [53] are a few in... p. 18, Undated
    - [55] Deponent he should not have..., 1734 June 3
    - [55] Deposition of John Depeyster, Mayor of Albany, 1734 December 3
    - [57] Deposition made by Philip Livingston at the Mayor's request, 1734 December 3
    - [57] Complaint by James Alexander and William Smith to the General Assembly, 1735
    - [59] Deposition of Johannes Wendell, Alderman, City of Albany, 1734 December 6
    - [59] Attestations of Richard Ashfield and Jen Tothill, merchants of New York, 1734 December 11
    - [59] Deposition of Johannes Vissher, Alderman, City of Albany, 1734 December 6
    - [59] Attestations of Richard Ashfield and others, Undated
    - [61] Letter from certain Indians addressed, it is supposed to Philip Livingston, 1762 March 17
    - [61] Deposition of Dierck Ten Brocek, Recorder of Albany, 1734 December 7
    - [62] Engagement made with Philip Livingston by Sachems of upper Castle of Maquass, 1729 January 25
    - [62] Letter to John Peter Zenger, 1734 October 9
    - [63] Deposition by Thomas Brown, 1734 December 9
    - [63] I happened to be in Company..., 1734 October 9
    - [65] Two of the grand jury..., Undated
    - [65] City of New York..., 1734 December 9
    - [65] Deposition of Nicholas Governeur and Robert Livingston, Jr., Merchants, 1733 December 9
    - [67] Copy of paragraph in letter from James Alexander to John McCulloch, &c., 1733 September 6
    - [67] Copy of paragraph of letter from John McCulloch to James Alexander, 1733 December 16
    - [67] Deposition made by James Alexander, 1733 December 9
    - [67] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1734 December 22
    - [67] Copies Gentlemen, 1734
    - [69] Letter from William Smith to James Alexander, 1734 December 25
    - [71] Proposals of what..., Undated
    - [71] I find in Bradford's Gazette, Undated
    - [71] Copy of letter to the publisher of "Journal" replying to one published in "Gazette", Undated
    - [71] Proposals of what Colonel Lewis Morris is expected to do in England, Undated
    - [73] Letter from William Smith to James Alexander, Undated
    - [73] That the Subscribers..., 1734 November 19
    - [73] Proposed instructions to Colonel Lewis Morris as his course while in England, 1734 December 19
    - [73] Considerations and alterations in the instructions to Colonel Lewis Morris, Undated
    - [74] Memorandum of amounts to be paid towards Colonel Lewis Morris' expenses, Undated
    - [75] Names of those agreeing to sustain Colonel Lewis Morris, Undated
    - [75] Instructions, Undated
    - [77] The case of Lewis Morris, Esq. - late Chief Justice to be had before Com. Privy Council, 1735
    - [79] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 July 1
    - [79] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 July 12
    - [80] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 July 22
    - [81] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to Mary Alexander, 1735 November 27
    - [81] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 November 20
    - [81] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 November 28
    - [81] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 November 27
    - [81] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 November 29
    - [81] Copy of survey of a tract of land sent to James Alexander, 1735 April
    - [83] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1744 November 2
    - [85] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 December 3
    - [85] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 December 5
    - [87] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 December 27
    - [87] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 February 22
    - [87] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 March 1
    - [89] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 April 6
    - [89] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 April 22
    - [89] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736
    - [91] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1736 December 24
    - [91] Letter from Lewis Morris, Jr. to James Alexander, 1735 November 18
    - [93] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1736 January 23
    - [93] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 March 29
    - [95] Draughts of letters, 1734 December 30
    - [95] Copy of a letter from James Alexander to Lewis Morris, 1734 December 30
    - [95] Draft of letter from James Alexander to Lewis Morris, 1735 January 6
    - [95] Draft of a letter from James Alexander to Lewis Morris, 1735 January 17
    - [95] Draft of letter from James Alexander to Lewis Morris, 1735 February 4
    - [97] Draft of paragraph from James Alexander to Lewis Morris, 1735 January
    - [97] Draughts of letters, 1735 June
    - [101] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 January 1
    - [101] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 January 3
    - [103] Letter from Vincent Matthews to James Alexander, 1735 January 4
    - [103] Affidavit of Thomas Marsh, 1734 December 30
    - [103] Affidavit to Thomas Marsh, 1734 December 31
    - [103] Letter from Philip Livingston to James Alexander, 1735 January 7
    - [103] Letter from Vincent Matthews to James Alexander, 1735 January 5
    - [105] Copy of His Majesty's Order dismissing Lewis Morris, Jr. from Council, 1734 February 3
    - [105] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1734 February 8
    - [105] Letter from W. Allen to James Alexander, 1735 February 7
    - [105] Trusty and well beloved..., 1730 April 23
    - [105] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 February 19
    - [107] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 March 4
    - [107] Letter from William Smith to James Alexander, 1735
    - [109] A paper for Zenger apparently in the writing of Lewis Morris, Undated
    - [111] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 March 12
    - [113] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 February 24
    - [115] Letter from William Smith to James Alexander, Undated
    - [115] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 March 30
    - [115] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 March 31
    - [117] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 April 13
    - [117] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 April 15
    - [119] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 April 23
    - [119] Letter from John Kinson to Messrs. Alexander, Smith, and Others, 1735 May 16
    - [121] Letter from Lewis Morris, Undated
    - [121] Letter from Lewis Morris, Jr. to James Alexander, Undated
    - [123] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 July 29
    - [123] Draft of letter from James Alexander to Lewis Morris, 1735 June 21
    - [123] Copy of a letter from James Alexander to Lewis Morris, 1735 July 8
    - [125] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 August 1
    - [125] Letter from Vincent Matthews to James Alexander, 1735 August 12
    - [127] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 August 9
    - [127] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 August 20
    - [129] Letter from Lewis Morris, Undated
    - [129] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 August 20
    - [129] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 August 25
    - [131] Copies of letter to Philip Livingston, Albany, 1735 September
    - [131] Letter from James Alexander to Philip Livingston, 1735 October 6
    - [133] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 September 23
    - [133] Letter from Lewis Morris, Undated
    - [135] Copy of Colonel Henry Beekman's Will made in New York, 1726 September 26
    - [137] Letter from Philip Livingston to James Alexander, 1735 October 11
    - [137] Letter from Gilbert Livingston, 1735 October 11
    - [137] Citation from the Governor to Gilbert and Cornelia Livingston, 1735 September 23
    - [139] Letter from Philip Livingston to James Alexander, 1735 October 15
    - [139] Petition from certain citizens of Albany to New York Assembly, 1735 October
    - [139] Draught of Albany Petition, 1735 October
    - [141] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1735 October 24
    - [143] Copies of letters, 1735 November 6
    - [143] Draft of a letter from James Alexander to Lewis Morris, 1735 December 15
    - [145] Letter from Lewis Morris, Jr. to James Alexander, 1735 November 11
    - [145] Letter from Peter Collinson to James Alexander, 1735 November 8
    - [147] Attestation of Johannes Berger, Alderman of New York City, 1735 December 16
    - [147] Letter from Vincent Matthews to James Alexander, 1735 November 27
    - [147] Copy of order for suspension of Rip Van Dam from Council, 1735 November 24
    - [149] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1735 December 27
    - [151] Allegorical history of Governor Cosby's Administration in the writing of James Alexander, Undated
    - [153] Thomas Stagger's communication to Peter Zenger, Publisher of "N.Y. Journal", Undated
    - [155] Notes of facts demanded by Defendants in case of Murray Crymble vs. Henry Cruger, 1736
    - [156] A paper for the journal, Undated
    - [159] "Cormark O'Neal's" communication to Peter Zenger, publisher of "Journal", Undated
    - [161] "Vincit amor Patrice" A communication to Peter Zenger in the writing of William Smith, Undated
    - [163] The Museum, Undated
    - "The Maxim of the Modern Politician," an article for Peter Zenger's paper in the writing of William Smith, Undated
    - [165] An article for Zenger's "N.Y. Journal" from Lewis Morris, Undated
    - [167] p. 5-8, Undated
    - [169] A communication from an anonymous contributor, Undated
    - [169] p. 9-10, Undated
    - [171] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1736 January 4
    - [171] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1736 January 11
    - [173] Letter from Vincent Matthews to James Alexander, 1736 January 13
    - [175] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 February 5
    - [175] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 January 16
    - [177] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1736 February 25
    - [177] An anonymous communication for Zenger brought to James Alexander, 1736 March 2
    - [179] Letter from Andrew Hamilton to James Alexander, 1736 March 18
    - [179] Letter from Andrew Hamilton to James Alexander, 1736 March 10
    - [179] Letter from Rip Van Dam to James Alexander, 1736 March 11
    - [179] Letter from Messrs. Alexander and Smith to Rip Van Dam, 1736 March 11
    - [181] A clause in the King's Commission to Governor William Cosby, Undated
    - [183] Zenger, 1736
    - [183] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 May 25
    - [183] Advice to John Peter Zenger, Undated
    - [183] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1736 May 25
    - [185] Letter from Philip Livingston to James Alexander, 1736 August 14
    - [185] Draft of letter from James Alexander presumed to be Cadwallader Colden, 1736 August 26
    - [187] City Hall May it please, 1740 September 23
    - [187] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1737 May 21
    - [187] John Peter Zenger, 1740 September 27
    - [187] An address to the New York Assembly from John Lesley to be presented by James Alexander, Member of the House, Undated
    - [189] Letter from James Sterl to James Alexander, 1737 December 1
    - [189] At a Supreme Court, 1737 October 18
    - [189] Order of court for restoration of Messrs. Alexander and Smith, as attorneys, Undated
    - [191] Certificate of Election of James Alexander as Member of Assembly, 1737 December 16
    - [191] Certificate of attendance of James Alexander as Member of Assembly from Lewis Morris, Jr., 1738 October 19
    - [191] Memorandum from James Alexander of purpose of appropriation of his pay as Member of Assembly, Undated
    - [193] Computation, 1737 December
    - [193] Part of XV, 1737
    - [193] Credit Report, 1737 December
    - [193] Rough draft of proposed Bill of Credit, 1737 December
    - [195] Letter from David Provoost to James and Mary Alexander, 1740 October 26
    - [197] Letter from George Graham to Peter Collinson enclosed to James Alexander, 1741 February 17
    - [199] Letter from Benjamin Franklin to James Alexander, 1741 March 6
    - [199] Letter from James and Mary Alexander to David Provoost, 1741 April 22
    - [201] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1741 November 4
    - [201] Agreement as to legal changes made between William Smith and others, 1741 September 1
    - [201] Letter from James Wilcox to James Alexander, 1741 September 15
    - [203] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1742 June 21
    - [205] Letter from Richard Peters to James Alexander, 1742 July 14
    - [207] Letter from Robert Charles to James Alexander, 1742 August 31
  - Subseries I.D: Volume III, 1742-1766
    TBD including William Alexander's involvement with the French and Indian War
    - [1] To Be Sold, 1762 December 13
    - [1] By Vertue of an Order, 1720
    - [1] Warrant, 1724 June 1
    - [1] Prentis, 1728
    - [1] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1742 July 31
    - [5] Letter from Philip Livingston to James Alexander, 1742 September 8
    - [5] Copy of a letter from Robert Charles to Horace Walpole, 1742 July 31
    - [5] Copy of a letter from Horace Walpole to Robert Charles, 1743 August 4
    - [5] Copy of a letter from Robert Charles to Horace Walpole, 1742 August 12
    - [5] Copy of a letter from Horace Walpole to Robert Charles, 1742 August 16
    - [7] Letter from P.V.B. Livingston to James Alexander, 1742 September
    - [9] Letter from Alexander Colden and William Smith to James Alexander, 1743 June 19
    - [9] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1743 August 31
    - [9] Proposition from Alexander, Colden, &c, to purchase certain lands, Undated
    - [11] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1743 December 5
    - [11] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1743 December 15
    - [13] Letter from Lewis Morris to James Alexander, 1744 March 2
    - [13] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1743 December 15
    - [14] Letter from Cadwallader Colden to James Alexander, 1744 November 9
    - [15] Draught of a letter, 1745 January 4
    - [15] Memorandum of meeting held in New York by James Alexander, 1745 January 3
    - [15] Draft of a general letter by James Alexander embodying the sentiments of a meeting held in New York, 1745 January 3
    - [17] Copy of order from James Alexander on John Wilcox for certain books, 1748 April 30
    - [17] Letter from William Alexander to James Alexander, 1751 February 14
    - [17] Draft of a communication made by the Governor to the Council of the Province of New York, 1751 June
    - [17] Letter from Robert Morris to James Alexander, 1747 February 24
    - [17] Draft of a letter from James Alexander to Robert Morris, 1747 March 3
    - [19] Letter from the Governor to Captain Roddem of the Navy in writing of James Alexander, Undated
    - [21] Letter from William Bull Jr. to P.V.B. Livingston, 1752 March 24
    - [21] Letter from Benjamin Franklin to James Alexander, 1752 January 8
    - [23] Letter from Benjamin Pomeroy to P.V.B. Livingston, 1753 March 7
    - [23] Communication from "The Independent Reflector" to James Alexander, 1753 March 8
    - [23] Letter from William Bull, Jr. to P.V.B. Livingston, 1752 May 11
    - [23] Letter from William Bull to P.V.B. Livingston, 1752 May 14
    - [24] Letter from J. Hopson to Messrs. Alexander and Livingston, 1753 July 13
    - [25] Letter from Housman Broadley to William Alexander, 1755 June 18
    - [25] Letter from Housman Broadley to William Alexander, 1755 June 15
    - [25] Letter from Housman Broadley to William Alexander, 1755 June 17
    - [27] Letter from William Alexander to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 July 5
    - [27] Letter from William Alexander to P.V.B. Livingston, Undated
    - [29] Letter from Henry Wendell to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 July 9
    - [29] Henry Wendell, 1755 July 21
    - [29] Letter from William Alexander to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 July 8
    - [31] Captain Housman Broadley, 1755 September 2
    - [31] Letter from Housman Broadley to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 August 31
    - [33] Letter from John Luforcy to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 September 27
    - [33] Letter from Benjamin Stakes to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 September 9
    - [34] Letter from Housman Broadley to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 October 6
    - [35] Letter from Richard Peters to Messrs. Alexander & Livingston, 1755 September 23
    - [35] Letter from John St. Clair to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 November 1
    - [35] Letter from Richard Peters to Livingston and Alexander, 1755 November 23
    - [35] Letter from Housman Broadley to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 October 20
    - [36] Appointment of George Cradock and others as Auditors, 1756 April 15
    - [37] Letter from Henry Wendell to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 April 15
    - [37] Letter from Isaac Wendell to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 December 10
    - [37] Letter from John Laforsy to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 December 12
    - [37] G. Cradock et al., 1756 April 15
    - [38] Appointment of George Cradock and others as Examiners of accounts, 1756 July 31
    - [35] Certificate of George Cradock and others as to the correctness of accounts, Undated
    - [39] Letter from William Coxe to Messrs. Alexander and Livingston, 1756 July 18
    - [39] Letter from William Alexander to his sister, 1756 June 12
    - [39] By the Honorable Spencer Phips, 1756 July 31
    - [41] Letter from L. Beliher to William Alexander, 1756 November 1
    - [41] Appointment of George Cradock and others as Auditors of Accounts, 1756 July 31
    - [41] Certificate from George Cradock and others upon examination of accounts, 1756 August 23
    - [41] Map of Fort George, Undated
    - [43] Order from General James Abercrombie for recruiting men, Undated
    - [43] Reasons for General Ambercrombie's changing Regimental Agent and his reply, Undated
    - [45] By His Excellency James Abercrombie, 1758 November 3
    - [45] Letter from Robert Livingston to P.V.B. Livingston, 1757 April 27
    - [47] Letter from John Brainerd to P.V.B. Livingston, 1758 July 11
    - [47] Aaron Burr to William Alexander, 1757 May 4
    - [47] Letter from Archibald Gordon to P.V.B. Livingston, 1757 December 23
    - [49] Letter from P.V.B. Livingston to a Mr. Earll, 1760 February 27
    - [49] An anonymous article criticizing the course of the ministry, towards the colonies in conducting the war, Undated
    - [51] Draft of agreement amongst certain gentlemen for the employment of one Malcolm as a teacher, Undated
    - [51] Letter from Robert R. Livingston, 1767 January 20
    - [52] Letter from Sir William Johnson to Arms Bradt, 1768 March 18
    - [53] Letter from William Alexander to John Petrie, 1755 January 4
    - [55] Orders and Instructions, 1755 April 24
    - [55] Orders and Instructions from General Shirley to John Erving, Jr., William Alexander, and Lewis Morris, Jr., Merchants of N.Y., 1755 April 24
    - [55] Appointment by General Shirley of Messrs. Erving, Alexander, and Morris for supplying the army with provisions, 1755
    - [57] Letter from Governor Robert Dinwiddie of Virginia to William Alexander, 1755 May 3
    - [57] W. Allen, 1755 April 24
    - [57] Orders and Instructions from General Shirley to William Alexander, 1755 April 28
    - [57] Letter from Sir William Pepperell to Miss Livingston, 1755 March 25
    - [57] Directions of two vessels to be built at Oswego, 1755
    - [59] Notice of proceedings of Council of Province of Virginia, 1755 May 26
    - [59] Agreeable to my promise..., 1755 May 3
    - [61] Letter from General William Shirley to Governor James DeLancey, 1755 May 26
    - [61] Letter from General William Shirley to Governor James DeLancey, 1755 May 26
    - [63] Copy of a warrant from General William Shirley to John Erving, Jr., 1755 June 20
    - [65] Letter from Governor Robert Dinwiddie to Messrs. Alexander and Livingston, 1755 June 2
    - [67] Letter from William Alexander to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 August 4
    - [69] Letter from General William Shirley to Oliver DeLancey, 1755 September 29
    - [71] Copy of Act of Assembly of N.Y. for selling certain provisions, 1755
    - [71] Orders from General William Shirley to Colonel Thomas Dunbar, 1755 August 6
    - [73] Letter from Ann Shirley to her friend Mrs. Parker, 1755 June 10
    - [75] Copy of a letter from William Alexander to James Stevenson, 1755 September
    - [77] Letter from William Alexander to P.V.B. Livingston, 1755 September 18
    - [77] Proceedings of a meeting of Council in N.Y., 1755 September 24
    - [79] Memorial from the Merchants of New York in relation to the Sugar Act, Undated
    - [79] The case of the Province of New York in relation to the Sugar Bill, Undated
    - [81] Letter from William Alexander to John Cuyler, 1756 January 2
    - [83] Letter from William Alexander and James Stevenson, 1756 January 3